Okay, so that was your introduction to Hugging Face.
얼굴 껴안기는 여기까지였어요
And now I'm going to turn to a different resource available which is Google Colab.
이제 다른 리소스로 넘어가죠 구글 Colab이에요
There are a bunch of different alternatives to Google Colab that all do much the same thing, and you
구글 콜랍을 대체할 수 있는 다양한 방법이 있어요 다 똑같은 기능이고
can really use any of them.
아무거나 사용해도 돼요
I like Colab in particular for a couple of reasons.
콜랍이 좋은 이유가 두 가지 있어요
One of them is that so many people use it.
그중 하나는 너무 많은 사람이 쓴다는 거죠
And another is it's so easy to share, but let's just talk about what it is.
다른 하나는 공유하기 쉽다는 거예요 하지만 뭔지 얘기해보죠
So Google Colab, um, it's a it's a few things.
구글 콜랍은 몇 가지에 해당해요
But the reason, the main thing that it is, and what we're going to do with it, is the ability to
하지만 이 제품의 주요한 이유이자 앞으로 할 일은 우리가
run a Jupyter notebook like the ones we've been using, and run it in the cloud on a Google box, which
사용한 것처럼 Jupyter 노트북을 실행하는 겁니다 구글 박스의 클라우드에서
will have not only a decent CPU, but also a GPU that might be high spec, uh, and uh, in addition
실행하면 괜찮은 CPU뿐 아니라 고사양 GPU도 갖추게 되죠 그뿐 아니라 Jupyter
to that, the thing that I like about it is that you can share and collaborate your Jupyter notebook
노트북을 다른 제품과 공유하고 협력할 수 있다는 게 좋아요 익숙한
with others using the same kind of familiar interface.
인터페이스를 사용해서요
You can use to share other types of Google Doc.
다른 유형의 구글 문서를 공유할 때 사용할 수 있죠
So if, like me, you're very used to using Google Docs and Google Sheets and the like and sharing them
저처럼 구글 문서나 구글 시트를 사용하는 데 익숙하고 공유하고
and editing them and so on, then it's a very familiar experience to be able to share and collaborate
편집하는 데 익숙하다면 콜랍에 있는 주피터 공책에 공유하고
on a Jupyter notebook running in Colab.
협업하는 건 아주 익숙한 경험이죠
Uh, and it's also integrated with other Google services.
다른 구글 서비스와도 통합돼 있어요
So for example, you can very easily access your own Google Drive if you have data there or something
예를 들어, 데이터가 있다면 구글 드라이브에 쉽게 접근할
like that.
수 있죠
So it's it's nicely part of the Google ecosystem.
구글 생태계의 멋진 일부죠
But as I say, there are a bunch of other offerings.
하지만 말씀드렸듯이 다른 공물도 많아요
And you can if you if you're using a something that is a competitor to Google Colab and you like it,
여러분이 구글 Colab의 경쟁사 제품을 사용하고 있고 그게 마음에 든다면
then by all means use it.
얼마든지 사용하세요
Uh, you may have to, uh, copy across the colab that I'll be using in sharing, but otherwise everything
공유에 사용할 콜라브를 복사해야 할 수도 있지만 그것만 빼면 다
should work just fine.
괜찮을 거예요
When you're using Colab, you get to choose what runtimes you're working with, what kind of box it's,
Colab을 사용할 때는 어떤 런타임을 사용할 것인지 어떤 종류의 박스를 사용할 것인지 어떤 종류의
what kind of VM is essentially, uh, running.
VM을 실행할 것인지 선택해야 하죠
There are CPU based boxes which don't have a GPU, are just CPUs.
CPU 기반의 박스는 GPU가 없고 그냥 CPU죠
There is, uh, there are lower spec boxes running cheaper GPUs, and then there's higher spec, beefier
저렴한 GPU를 사용하는 저사양 박스도 있고 자원 집약적인 엔진을 위한
boxes for resource intensive stuff.
고사양의 튼튼한 박스도 있죠
Everything that we do in this course can run on on up to number two, the lower spec GPU runtimes.
이 코스에서 하는 모든 건 2번까지 실행할 수 있습니다 하위 사양 GPU 런타임이죠
I'm going to be trying my absolute best to keep it so that you can do everything and not spend anything,
최선을 다해서 가게를 지킬 테니 재료비 걱정은 하지 말고 필요한
any material amount of money.
건 뭐든 하세요
Um, perhaps at this point, if you, if we if you go as far as training a full deep neural network
이 시점에서 당신이 직접 심층 신경망을 훈련한다면
yourself, we might be starting to talk about, uh, a few dollars, but nothing that's going to break
몇 달러 정도 들겠지만 큰돈은 안 들 거예요 한 단계 더 나아가서
the bank, I hope, uh, unless you wish to take it a step further and train faster, do more experimenting.
더 빨리 훈련하고 더 많은 실험을 하고 싶지 않다면요
In which case, you certainly have the ability to opt for number three and spend a little bit more.
3번째 비트를 선택하고 좀 더 많은 돈을 쓸 수 있죠
Uh, and again, we're talking about maybe spending $10 to get a decent, like, a day or two's worth
다시 말씀드리지만 10달러 정도 들여서 하루 이틀 정도
of work, uh, against a top end GPU box.
작업하면 최고의 GPU 박스가 완성될 거예요
So without further ado, that's a quick intro.
그럼 지체 없이 간단히 소개를 마칠게요
Let's go in and take a look at Colab and get comfortable with it.
콜랍을 살펴보고 익숙해지도록 하죠 Get